No, we are not there yet,
不 我们还没到
but it should be just past this ridge, Bumbobee.
不过应该就在这山崖后面 大黄蜂
I don’t get it. These readings are off the metre.
我不明白 读数爆表了
I told you, doc, we are fine.
我跟你说过了 医生 我们没事！
The only way to be certain you are fine, Bulkhead,
惟一确认你没事的方法 隔板
is to enduring standard defrosting procedure.
是耐心接受标准除霜处理
You know prolonged exposure to sub-zero conditions
你清楚长期暴露在低温下
can cause permanent system damage.
会造成永久性系统损伤
Ratchet, have you learned anything more about our Arctic find.
救护车 我们在北极发现的东西你调查清楚了吗？
Not yet.
还没有
The pod can’t be opened while it’s frozen solid.
舱门被冻住了 暂时打不开
Arcee and I will search for any clue
阿尔茜和我去调查
which might explain the origin of our arctic find.
这个从北极来的东西究竟源自何方
Only until your sensors sound.
感应器一响就马上回来
Remember, once your core temperature drops into the blue zone,
记住 如果你的核心温度降至蓝色区域
system failures are likely. They are eminent.
很可能发生系统瘫痪 后果很严重
Missed us doc bot?
想我们了吗 机器医生？
Uh, shouldn’t they be in school?
他们不是应该在上学吗？
On Saturday? We have the whole weekend off, to spend with you.
在星期六？我们整个周末都有空…来陪你
I wasn’t expecting a car pool.
我本来不想拼车的
What gives, Arcee?
什么情况 阿尔茜？
Tap team, Jack.
很诱人 杰克
It’s my turn for exploration duty.
轮到我执行探索任务
Oh, too bad.
噢 真不巧
It’s a beautiful day for a ride.
今天是个兜风的好日子
Would hate for you to feel guilty for leaving me indoors.
把我扔在家 你可能会有负罪感啊
Arctic exploration duty.
北极探索任务
Indoor’s where is warm.
那还是家里暖和
The Arctic?
北极？
I’ve always wanted to see snow.
我一直想去看雪呢
I would invite you to join, Raphael.
我很乐意邀你同行 拉斐尔
But the conditions are much too extreme.
但那里的条件过于恶劣
Even for we Autobots.
哪怕对我们汽车人来说
I... understand.
我…理解
But I will bring you back a snow ball.
不过 我会给你带一个雪球回来
That would be awesome!
那太棒了！
Transport complete.
传送完成
So, what do you guys think we should do today?
那么 你们说今天该干什么？
Video game turn! The last one standing wins!
电子游戏时间 看谁是最后的赢家！
Bulkhead, Bumbobee! Here, now!
隔板 大黄蜂 赶快过来！
Prepare to be destroyed!
准备受死吧！
Eh, yea, not really my thing, Miko.
嗯 没错 我不太擅长这个 神子
Oh, scared of losing to a girl?
噢 是怕输给女孩子吧？
No mercy.
绝不手软！
Hey Raf, you want to take on Miko for me?
嘿 拉夫 想替我摆平神子吗？
Nap, I have stuff to do.
不 我有事要做
You can't boss us around because the boss is out!
老大不在 你也不能随便使唤我们啊！
I need some heavy lifting. The ground bridge is down.
我需要人帮忙干活 环陆桥坏了！
Optimus and Arcee made it through just fine.
擎天柱和阿尔茜出发顺利
It's bringing them back that concerns me.
我担心的是怎么把他们接回来
Now remove those panels, chop, chop!
现在把那些仪表搬开 要快！
Temperature sub-zero and dropping...
气温在零下并持续下降
Not a... get back... to base...
不行了…得返回…基地
Hello?
有人吗？
Where did you come from?
你是哪儿来的？
You wanna play fetch?
想玩接东西吗？
No, don’t eat that!
不 别吃！
You’re gonna choke!
你会噎着的！
...or not?
或许…不会？
Come on, come on. You want some...
来吧 来吧 尝尝厉害…
Ate your face!
大获全胜！
What the...
怎…怎么回事？！
Great, power fail.
好极了 停电了！
Eh, it wiped out our game!
啊 我们的游戏被中断了！
You, but, uh,
你…怎么能
I was winning!
我明明赢了！
Bummer!
认了吧
We definitely have a problem.
我们一定是遇到了什么问题
But what could have caused this?
但到底是什么导致的这个…
Or that?
或是那个
Might be the main grid.
可能是主电网
Hopefully it isn't a substation malfunctioning.
但愿不是配电站的问题
Hey guys, look what I found?
嘿 伙计们 瞧我找到了什么？
We are busy! Ah!
我们很忙！
Hey, hey, what's with you guys?
嘿 嘿 你们怎么了？
Scraplet, scraplet!
吸屑虫！吸屑虫！！！
What's a scraplet?
吸屑虫是什么？
The most dangerous vermin ever to crawl upon the face of Cybertron.
塞博特恩有史以来最危险的害虫！
A this?
就它？
Are you kidding me?
你在开玩笑吗？
You are giant robots!
你们是巨型机器人！
Scrappy here is tiny.
而这虫虫…小得很
You have no idea the damage that tiny thing could do!
你没见识过这个小东西的破坏力！
Eh, he wouldn't hurt any thing.
啊 他不会伤害任何东西
Alright, easy there, killer.
行了 放松 小杀手
Whoa, I did not see that coming.
哇噢 我没想到会是这样
I'm sorry, Bumbobee.
对不起 大黄蜂！
Is it gonna be OK?
你会好起来吗？
Only a mesh wound,
只是皮外伤
he'll live.
他死不了
Now do you believe me?
你现在相信我了吧？
All scraplets do is dismantle machinery and eat anything metal,
吸屑虫会肢解机器 然后吃掉所有金属部分
especially living metal.
尤其是活的金属！
Well, bug squashed, game over, right?
那么 虫子已经被打扁了 应该没事了吧？
No.
不！
When it comes to Scraplets there is never just one.
吸屑虫绝不会独来独往
And I fear I know how they got in here.
恐怕我知道他们是怎么进来的了
It’s a trap,
这是个笼子
a Scraplet trap.
用来抓吸屑虫的！
Eh, an empty Scraplet trap?
嗯…空的吸屑虫笼子？
Most likely ejected into space eons ago.
可能是远古时期发射到太空的
Only to wind up in the Arctic when the temperature kept them in stasis.
最终掉到了北极 低温使他们一直休眠
Until we brought the thaw.
直到我们把他们弄出来
Now they are wide awaken and ready to branch.
现在他们苏醒过来 并蓄势待发
So...
那…
how many are we talking about?
他们有多少？
Thousands.
成百上千
The power malfunctions and ground bridge damage
电力故障和环陆桥的损坏
are sure signs that their infestation is well under way.
明确表明他们正在侵蚀这里
Arcee, what's your status?
阿尔茜 你的情况怎么样？
My sensors' are going off.
我的感应器响了
Guess we should call for pick up before things get chilling.
我们最好在冻僵之前打道回府
Optimus to base,
擎天柱呼叫基地
core temperature readings have reached the blue zone.
核心温度读数降至蓝色区域
Prepare to activate Ground Bridge.
准备启动环陆桥
Ratchet to Optimus, do you read me?
救护车呼叫擎天柱 你能听到吗？
We have a situation.
我们遇到了麻烦
Scraplets have got into the com-link system.
吸屑虫侵入了通讯系统！
If we don't eradicate these creatures immediately,
如果我们不立即清除这些生物
they will reduce the entire base to a scrappy.
他们会将整个基地变成一团废渣！
I say we bug out of here and let them keep it.
我说我们还是开溜 让他们占领好了！
Evacuation is not an option.
我们不能转移
If we don't get the Ground Bridge back online stat,
如果我们不修复环陆桥
Optimus and Arcee will perish.
擎天柱和阿尔茜会被冻死
The... Well...
那 好吧…
Bulkhead, you never run!
隔板 你从不退缩的！
Miko, you haven't seen the swarm of this thing devour a bot.
神子 你没见过一群虫子活吃机器人的情景
I have.
我见过
They pick you apart from the inside out.
他们从里到外把你拆开
Going for the small, juicy bits first,
从小而多汁的部分开始
fuse by fuse, circuit by circuit,
每根导线 每条电路
till there's nothing left.
吃个精光！
And I mean nothing!
我说的是精光！
Not even your optics.
连视觉电路都不剩
You have to let us help.
你得让我们帮忙
We are not made of metal.
我们不是金属做的
Yea, the Scraplets can't hurt us.
没错 吸屑虫伤不了我们
Typically, I find your fleshiness to be your least engaging quality,
通常 我觉得你们的血肉之躯是最不中用的
but it would appear to provide an advantage under these extremes.
但在极端情况下 似乎是一种优势
Ok, good.
很好
So we pair off. One bot, one human.
我们结伴行动 一个汽车人配一个人类
I'll watch your back while you repair the Ground Bridge.
我来掩护你维修环陆桥
And we go in a bug hunt.
那我们就去杀虫
Optimus to base, do you read.
擎天柱呼叫基地 听到了吗？
Are you sure a nice long drive wouldn’t help?
你觉得我们来个千里奔袭如何？
I hear Miami is beautiful this time of year.
我听说这个时节的迈阿密气候宜人
The nearest temperate climate is too distant, Arcee.
最近的温带地区离这里太远了 阿尔茜
Attempting to reach it would expend too much energy,
去那里要消耗太多能量
and hasten the freezing process.
会加快冰冻的速度
Until Ratchet sense for us,
要坚持到救护车找到我们
and he will.
他一定会的
Our best option will be to seek shelter,
眼下的明智之举是寻找避风港
and insolate ourselves.
以保持体温
I get to be your bodyguard for once, how cool is that?
我能当一回你的保镖 多么酷啊！
Raphe found the first one here, right? Ahhhh!
拉斐尔在这儿发现了第一个 对吧？
Did you just scream like a little girl?
你刚刚像小女孩一样尖叫了吗？
No.
没有！
Maybe.
或许吧
Can we talk about this later?
我们以后再讨论这个好吗？
Take it easy, Bulkhead.
别紧张 隔板
Just stay focused. Everything’s gonna be...
集中精神就好 一切都会…
Ah, my god, get out of me!
啊 我的天 离我远点！
OK, wish I hadn't seen that.
好吧 真希望我没看到这场面
Bulkhead, you are fine.
隔板 你没事！
It's just a bunch of cables.
那只是一些电缆
Eh, ho, right. Cables. Hehe.
嗯 对 电缆
Don't these things ever stop eating?
这些东西一直吃个不停吗？
How's it going over there?
那边进展得怎么样了？
I've repaired the damaged conductors,
我修好了受损的导体
and rerouted the central cond-roots;
重接了中央枢纽
But Ground Bridge still won't receive power!
可环陆桥还是无法恢复动力！
They fly?
它们会飞？
You never said they could fly!
你从没说过他们会飞！
Ratchet!
救护车！
The fire-extinguisher!
用灭火器！
Ratchet, get a patch kit.
救护车 准备急救包
We are leaking energon like... Wow!
我们的能量泄露得…哇哦！
Eat this! Ahhh!
吃这个吧！
Arcee, wake up.
阿尔茜 醒一醒！
The longer we remain alert,
我们保持清醒越久
the longer we remain alive.
就能存活越久
What do you suggest?
你有什么提议？
Wait, how about a game?
等等 不如玩个游戏？
Let's play "Who screwed  things up back at base".
我们来玩“猜猜基地里谁把事情搞砸了”
Our predicament could be the result of a simple malfunction.
一个简单的故障就有可能导致我们现在的困境
Caused by Bulkhead.
隔板惹的祸
Let's see. No com-link, maybe even no power.
想想看 通讯失灵 可能连动力都没了
The big lug probably tripped over a cord.
那个大块头很可能绊倒在了某根线上
He's never been too graceful.
他永远也学不会优雅
Remember when we first arrived on earth,
记得我们刚到地球的时候吗？
and Bulkhead walked into those power lines?
隔板踩到了供电线路
Bulkhead may be too large for this world,
隔板对这个世界来说或许过大了
but his inner strength is with our bond.
但他内在的力量与我们紧密相联
One should not be measured by size along.
不能单凭个头来评判一个人
We get them all?
把他们全消灭了吗？
Partly.
一部分
These were just scouts.
这些只是侦察兵
So the... rest of them know we're in here?
那么…剩下的那些知道我们在这儿了？
And if we allow ourselves to become their next meal,
如果我们成了他们的下一顿大餐
Optimus and Arcee will never make it home.
擎天柱和阿尔茜就再也回不来了
We must get the Ground Bridge operational.
我们必须让环陆桥运作起来！
Then we can use it to send Scraplets anywhere on earth.
然后用它把吸屑虫送到地球上的某处
Why not back to the Arctic?
直接送回北极怎么样？
We already know that they don't do cold.
我们已经知道他们怕冷
S-weet! One stop shopping!
好主意！一举两得！
Given the body mass of the Scraplets,
根据吸屑虫的体质 零度以下的低温
So think, Ratchet, think!
快想 救护车 快想想！
If the Ground Bridge is still down,
如果环陆桥还不能工作
there must be a breach in the energon fuel line!
只可能是能量输送管有裂口！
If we weren't breaching,
要不是我们也有裂口
one of us can get back over there and fix it.
就可以派一个人去修好它
Where do we find it?
输送管在哪儿？
And how do we fix it?
我们怎么修好它？
Remember, we are OK.
别怕 我们没事
We are not metal.
我们不是金属
There is the breach.
裂口在那儿！
Come on!
快！
We have to work fast!
我们得快点！
So if we get,
如果我们能…
when, we get the Ground Bridge open,
撑到环陆桥开启时
do we send the quippy crawlies out,
是先把这些爬虫送出去
or bring our bots in?
还是先把自己人接回来？
Optimus and Arcee will be fresh meat.
擎天柱和阿尔茜就像新鲜的鲜肉 如果他们先回来
We’ll need bait.
我们需要诱饵
Where are we gonna get bait?
我们到哪儿去找诱饵？
The Scraplets are already helping themselves to everything in here!
吸屑虫早就把这儿当成自己家了！
They are getting ready to feed！
他们准备开饭了！
You know the worst part?
你知道最糟糕的是什么吗？
After battling Cons all these years,
跟虎子们战斗了这么多年
getting smitten down, shot at, blown up,
被打躺过 射中过 炸飞过
this is how our lights go out?
结果却是这么个死法？
Arcee, This may not be the finish that we've planned,
阿尔茜 这或许不是我们意料中的结局
but if this is indeed the end,
但如果真要在这里结束
if we are to become one with the Allspark...
如果我们要和火种源融为一体…
It's been an honor serving with you, Optimus Prime.
和你一起战斗很荣幸 擎天柱
Ratchet, all systems go!
救护车 全修好了！
Fire it up!
发动它！
Ground Bridge,
环陆桥
activate...
启动…
Bait, eh?
诱饵 对吗？
Ready for the main course?
准备好用主菜了吗？
Come and get it! Ah!
来吃我啊！
Down, down!
卧倒 卧倒！
I'd invite you in,
我邀请你们进来
but the place is a mess.
不过家里一团糟
Report bio-circuitry status?
汇报生化电路情况？
Levels are rising.
正在恢复中
Excellent.
很好
Raphael, keep a close watch on Bumbobee's electro-pulse monitor.
拉斐尔 看好大黄蜂的电脉冲监视器
Miko, Check Bulkhead's interface patch.
神子 检查隔板的接口补丁
It's steady.
情况稳定
Looking good.
一切正常！
Perhaps you should get yourself some rest, old friend.
或许你也该休息一下了 老朋友
You saved quite a few lives today.
你今天拯救了众多的生命
It wasn't all my doing.
不…不全是我的功劳
We're just fortunate that this infestation happened...
我们不过是幸运地赶上侵蚀发生在…
on a Saturday.
星期六
Our human friends maybe small,
我们的人类朋友或许很渺小
but they are strong.
但他们很强大
A Scraplet?
又有吸屑虫？
Spider!
蜘蛛！
Is it on me? Ah eh oh oh oh...
它爬我身上了吗？
Did she just scream like a little girl?
她刚刚像小女孩一样尖叫了吗？